Mohamed Abo Elhassan Mohamed

Address: El cabanon, Attaka, Suez

Phone: 0100 670 1649

Email: abuelhassan615@gmail.com

SUMMARY

An experienced **Warehouse Senior Supervisor** with more than 12 years of experience in warehouses field (raw materials and final product). Efficient, dedicated, and self-motivated, with ability to work independently or collaboratively in a team environment. Through my experience I able to plan and implement proactive procedures and systems to avoid problems in the first place as well as having excellent communication skills, including ability to prepare and conduct presentation and reports to all levels of management, seeking employment that allows me to grow professionally while being able to utilize my skills for the growth of your organization with the best use of my knowledge, dedication, and determination.

EDUCATION

• Bachelor of Information Systems and Administrative, New Cairo Academy (May 2011)

> Cumulative grade: Very Good

> Graduation project grade: Excellent

EXPERIENCE

Savola, Attaka, Suez

(Jan 2012 – Present)

Warehouse Senior Supervisor

(Mar 2021 – Present)

- Supervise daily activities of the warehouse, including quality assurance, inventory control, space management, logistics, floor productivity, shipping, and customer service.
- Schedule and oversee warehouse team to meet the demands of the factory and manage the flow and quality of work to maximize efficiency and minimize overtime.
- Ensure implementation of the 5s strategy to make warehousing operations most effective.
- Meet regularly with warehouse leads to review, analyze, and develop actionable plans for productivity and loss prevention.
- Managing the warehouse in line with the company's standards.
- Ensure the proper storage of the finished products and raw materials by securing the optimum storage conditions.
- Complying with the company's policies and vision.
- Adhere to all warehousing, handling, and shipping legislation laws and requirements.
- Maintain standards of health and safety, hygiene, and security.
- Regularly update the data storage system.
- Recruit, select, orient, coach and motivate employees.
- Perform all necessary reports and share them with the Warehouse Operation Manager.
- Produce reports and statistics regularly (IN/OUT status report, dead stock, and slow-moving stock report etc).

➤ Warehouse Supervisor

- Plan, organize, supervise, and participate in daily warehouse operation and activities, including the receipt, documentation, storage, safety and distribution of equipment and supplies and maintenance of inventory.
- Train, supervise and evaluate the performance of assigned warehouse employees; assign workloads to warehouse workers.
- Receive, unpack, pack, load, issue, store and deliver materials, supplies or equipment; complete packing slips for shipments as assigned.
- Closely monitoring the daily reconciliation reports between warehouse and production stocks on SAP system.
- Take charge of stock control and warehouse organization.
- Route, schedule, pack and prepare orders for delivery; load vehicles; schedule and oversee deliveries and pick-ups.
- Supervise the processing of requisitions and requests to invoice for reimbursements of warehouse codes; complete requisitions for needed materials to assure adequate stock levels.
- Prepare and maintain a variety of records and logs and prepare reports as required; maintain inventory of items in the warehouse; file records as required; supervise the assembly of inventory printouts and catalogs as required.
- Ensure that the entire quantities of finished products and raw materials are properly entered on SAP system in order to access them easily at any time.

➤ Warehouse Specialist

(Jan 2012 - Dec 2014)

- Participate in daily warehouse operation and activities, including the receipt, documentation, storage, safety, and distribution of equipment and supplies and maintenance of inventory.
- Fulfilling orders, packaging items for shipment and arranging delivery pickups.
- Responsible for the loading and unloading of materials as well as verifying the quantity of items received against invoices.
- Monitor inventory levels in a warehouse.
- Create and affix warehouse labels.
- Communicating with other departments, such as shipping and accounting, to ensure all products are received and shipped in a timely manner.
- Providing customer service to customers who have questions about products or orders.
- Receiving shipments of goods from suppliers or manufacturers and unpacking or staging them for distribution within the warehouse.
- Keeping records of warehouse inventory levels and product locations to ensure all items are accounted for.
- Keep detailed shipping and receiving logs to account for all materials that enter and leave the warehouse.
- Responsible for organizing how and where materials are stored. Creating an efficient system and keeping a clean warehouse.

SKILLS

Language Skills:

- ➤ Mother tongue: Arabic
- Good command of both written and spoken English

Computer Skills:

- Oracle system user for more than 7 years.
- > SAP system user for more than 5 years.
- Good command of Microsoft Office software.
- Familiar with different computer system (Windows Vista, Windows 7 & 8).

TRAININGS

• Total Productive Maintenance (TPM) (Feb 2017 – Mar 2018)

Savola, Suez.

• Basics of firefighting (July 2013 – Aug 2013)

Savola, Suez.

Basic studies for Seamen (Sep 2010 – Jan 2011)

Arab Academy for Science, Technology & Maritime Transport.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth : 8/11/1990
Gender : Male
Nationality : Egyptian
Religion : Muslim
Marital Status : Married

Military Service: Exempted